WILLIAM KENNEDY PAPERS (MSS132) 1926-2003
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
William Kennedy Papers 1926-2003
nam_mss132
41.2
Kennedy, William, 1928-
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
The William Kennedy Papers document nearly a half century of research, writing, and publishing efforts of the internationally recognized, Pulitzer Prize winning author, playwright, essayist, journalist, script writer, professor, and champion of the arts. The collection consists of records related to all of Kennedy’s fiction and nonfiction books through 2002, including his "Albany Cycle" of novels, film scripts, essays, and newspaper articles from the Albany Times-Union. In addition, there is correspondence with other significant authors of American literature, biographical materials, and records documenting a trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland with President Bill Clinton.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in the William Kennedy Papers were acquired by the University at Albany Foundation and transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, between 2002 and 2005.
Alternative Formats Available
A photocopy of the original of the first draft of Legs in Series 2, box 1, folder 1 is available for review in the box for preservation reasons. The original is stored separately.
Biographical Sketch
William Kennedy, born 1928 in Albany, New York, is an award-winning author and journalist. He is best known for his “Albany Cycle” of eight published novels, one of which, Ironweed, received the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction in 1984.
Following his childhood and primary and secondary schooling in Albany, Kennedy attended nearby Siena College where he earned a bachelor of arts degree and edited the school's newspaper. Kennedy then began his professional literary career as a journalist at a local newspaper, followed by a U.S. Army newspaper during military service in Europe, the Albany Times-Union, and later as the managing editor of the San Juan Star in 1959. After attending Saul Bellow's fiction writing workshop at the University of Puerto Rico, he left his editorial position to focus on a career as a writer and subsequently returned to Albany in 1963. Kennedy initially wrote feature articles part-time for the Albany Times-Union about slum conditions and integration in the city that garnered him a Pulitzer Prize nomination and were later the inspiration for his nonfiction work O Albany! (1983). While serving as the Times-Union film critic, he released his first novel The Ink Truck (1969).
Beginning in 1975 with his novel Legs, Kennedy introduced his “Albany Cycle” of fiction, books that center upon the state capital and frequently focus on the struggles of recurrent characters, most notably the extended Phelan family. To date he published seven additional novels in this series, most recently Chango’s Beads and Two-Tone Shoes (2011). Kennedy also co-authored two children’s books with his son Brendan Kennedy, Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine (1986), and Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose (1993). His first play, Grand View (1996) appeared at the Capital Repertory Theatre in Albany. Kennedy released a second nonfiction book, Riding the Yellow Trolley Car, in 1993, a collection of essays, interviews, and human interest stories from the past 40 years.
Kennedy also garnered attention with his screenplay writing. He co-wrote The Cotton Club (1984) with the movie’s director Francis Ford Coppola. He penned the script for the film version of his novel Ironweed (1987).
In addition to his own writing career, Kennedy serves as a cultural and educational mentor to others in the field. Kennedy is the founder and executive director of the University at Albany-based New York State Writers Institute. He joined the University at Albany’s English Department in 1974, teaching creative writing and journalism as an instructor until 1982, and now serves as a professor. He also taught at Cornell University in 1982-1983 and was professor at the University of Oregon from 2001-2002.
Today Kennedy is an elected member of the American Academy of Arts and Letters and the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, and serves on the board of directors of the New York State Council for the Humanities. In addition to his Pulitzer Prize, he also received many other awards and accolades including a National Book Critics Circle Award, a MacArthur Fellowship (Genius Award), part of which served to establish the Writers Institute, a National Endowment for the Arts Fellowship, and a Regents Medal of Excellence from the State University of New York.
Kennedy met and married his wife Dana Sosa while working in Puerto Rico, and the couple has three adult children.
Bibliography
Materials authored by William Kennedy.
Fiction
The Ink Truck, 1969
Legs, 1975
Billy Phelan's Greatest Game, 1978
Ironweed, 1983
Quinn's Book, 1988
Very Old Bones, 1992
The Flaming Corsage, 1996
Roscoe, 2002
Chango's Beads and Two-Toned Shoes, 2011
Non-Fiction
O Albany!: Improbable City of Political Wizards, Fearless Ethnics, Spectacular Aristocrats, Splendid Nobodies, and Underrated Scoundrels, 1983
Riding the Yellow Trolley Car, 1993
Screenplays
Ironweed, 1987
The Cotton Club, co-authored with Francis Ford Coppola, 1984
Plays
Grand View, 1996
Children's Books Co-Authored with Brendan Kennedy
Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine, 1986
Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose, 1993
Scope and Content Information
The William Kennedy Papers document nearly a half century of research, writing, and publishing efforts of the internationally recognized, Pulitzer Prize winning author, playwright, essayist, journalist, script writer, professor, and champion of the arts. Born and raised in Albany, New York, Kennedy’s novels and nonfiction works frequently evoke a strong sense of place in the state capital, centering upon the city, its history, and its people during the nineteenth and twentieth centuries.
Kennedy transferred his materials to the M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives at the University at Albany through a series of acquisitions beginning in 2002. The collection features records related to all of Kennedy’s fiction and nonfiction books through 2002 as well as essays and newspaper articles from the Albany Times-Union. Well-known for embodying the heart of Albany in his work, Kennedy’s donations include extensive material from his “Albany Cycle” of novels, most prominently the Pulitzer Prize winning Ironweed (1984). However, his earlier works like Legs (1975) and more recent endeavors, such as The Flaming Corsage (1996) and Roscoe (2002) are also well represented. Kennedy also wrote two children’s books with his son, with related papers in the collection. All the files chronicle Kennedy’s meticulous research, writing, publishing, and promotion processes and feature proposals, numerous drafts with edits, rewrites, galleys, page proofs, correspondence, reviews, interviews, residual checks, and printed ephemera.
The Kennedy Papers also chart the transition of novels to film; Kennedy’s own Ironweed, filmed in the Albany area, which appeared on the big screen in 1987, and James Haskins’ The Cotton Club from 1984 for which Kennedy co-wrote the screen play with director Francis Ford Coppola. Relevant papers include working drafts, shooting scripts, looping and line scripts, production notes, call sheets, shooting schedules, and cast lists. In addition the collection has materials related to movie premieres, public relations efforts to market the films, and critics’ reviews.
Kennedy’s correspondence files demonstrate his significant role in late twentieth and early twenty-first century American literature and the arts and offer insights into relationships with other key figures in American literature. Letters detail his close friendships and associations with fellow authors, most notably mentor Saul Bellow and Hunter S. Thompson, as well as John Cheever, Frank McCourt, Joyce Carol Oates, and Philip Roth. The collection also features exchanges with journalists, poets and New York politicians, including Gay Talese, Andy Rooney, and former governor Mario Cuomo.
In addition to having a dedicated series for each of Kennedy's fiction and nonfiction books through 2002, both film scripts, children's books, and correspondence, the papers feature series devoted to related work and other endeavors. The collection holds Kennedy's professional and personal research, interviews, essays, and newspaper articles. In 1995 Kennedy accompanied President Clinton on a trip to Ireland and Northern Ireland as Clinton engaged in key peacemaking efforts. The collection includes background information briefings for the visit, correspondence, and news clips.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - The Ink Truck, 1954-2000, Undated
Series 2 - Legs, 1926-1988, Undated
Series 3 - Billy Phelan's Greatest Game, 1973, 1976-1978, 1985-1986, Undated
Series 4 - Ironweed, 1970, 1978-1982, 2003, Undated
Series 5 - O Albany!, 1953-2002, Undated
Series 6 - Charlie Malarkey Books, 1975-1998, 2001, Undated
Series 7 - The Cotton Club, 1983-1986, 1988-1989, 1993, 1997, Undated
Series 8 - Ironweed (Film Version), 1981-1997, Undated
Series 9 - Quinn's Book, 1981-1988, Undated
Series 10 - Very Old Bones, 1983, 1988-1993, Undated
Series 11 - Riding the Yellow Trolley Car, 1946-1999, Undated
Series 12 - The Flaming Corsage, 1993-1997, 2001, Undated
Series 13 - Roscoe, 1996-2000, Undated
Series 14 - The Albany Cycle, 1976, 1996, 2001-2002
Series 15 - Essays and Articles, 1963-1970 1972, 1978-1998, 2002, Undated
Series 16 - Correspondence, 1950, 1959-2003, Undated
Series 17 - Investigative Journalism, 1957-1998, Undated
Series 18 - Biographical, 1969, 1983-2003, Undated
Series 19 - Trip to Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland with President Clinton, 1990, 1993-1996, 1998, Undated
The materials are arranged chronologically for each series except for Series 5: O Albany!, Series 14: Essays and Series 16: Correspondence, which are arranged alphabetically by subject. Series dedicated to literary projects chart the development of each respective effort, generally with working and edited drafts and notes filed first, followed by final drafts, and then related correspondence, reviews, and publicity efforts also arranged by date.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature; Albany, New York; Kennedy, William, 1928-; Bellow, Saul; Cheever, John; Clinton, Bill, 1946-; McCourt, Frank; Oates, Joyce Carol, 1938-; Roth, Philip; Thompson, Hunter S.; Diamond, Legs, 1895 or 6-1931; Kennedy, William, 1928- Interviews; Kennedy, William, 1928- Ironweed; Kennedy, William, 1928---Authorship; Kennedy, William, 1928---Film and video adaptations; The Ink Truck; Legs; Billy Phelan's Greatest Game; Ironweed; O Albany!: Improbable City of Political Wizards, Fearless Ethnics, Spectacular Aristocrats, Splendid Nobodies, and Underrated Scoundrels; Cotton Club (Motion picture: 1984); Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine; Ironweed (Motion picture); Quinn's Book; Very Old Bones; Riding the Yellow Trolley Car; Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose; The Flaming Corsage; Grand View; Roscoe; American fiction; American essays; Pulitzer Prizes; Albany (N.Y.); Correspondence; Manuscripts for publication; Screenplays; Essays; Galley proofs; Drafts (documents); Clippings
Container List
- The Ink Truck, 1954-2000; Undated; 1; 2.1
  Arranged chronologically.
  Contains materials about Kennedy's first novel The Ink Truck, initially published in 1969 and then re-issued in 1984 following his success with Ironweed and his receiving the MacArthur Foundation's Genius Award. The novel details the last days of an unsuccessful newspaper strike and is very loosely based on Kennedy's experiences during a newspaper strike in Albany in the mid-1960s. The series includes multiple manuscript drafts, author's notes, book reviews, galleys, publisher agreements and correspondence, and advertising. Please note that the overall series dates are not inclusive.
  - Working Copy of First Draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - First Draft, Opening Section Removed, Copies 1-2, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Revisions to Second Draft, Author's Note Included, 2000; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Revisions to Second Draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Second Draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Revisions to Third Draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Completed Third Draft, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Third Draft, Copies 1-2, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Final Copy of Third Draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Working Copy of Third Draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Rewritten Pages of Fourth Draft, For Dial Press, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Working Copy of Fourth Draft, For Dial Press, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Completed Fourth Draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fourth Draft, Author Notes Included, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Dial Press Manuscript with Editor's Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Ink Truck Short Story Versions, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Excerpts The Black Beauty Spot, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Excerpts The A Coffin Full of Love, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Excerpts The Ink Truck (It Arrives, Bailey Meets It), Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Excerpts Prologue to a Novel "Legs", Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Drafts with Notes (Folder 1 of 2), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Drafts with Notes (Folder 2 of 2), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Author's Notes, 1968; Undated (Box 4, Folder 2-5)
  - Author's Notebook, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Book Galleys, 1969 (Oversized 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Publicity, Galleys, and Book Design, 1969; 1984; Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 3)
  - Research Articles and Reviews, 1954; 1964; 1969 (Oversized 1, Folder 4)
  - Research Articles from The Guild Reporter, 1964 (Oversized 1, Folder 5)
  - Research Materials for Newspaper Guild, Local 34, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Research Materials, Newspaper Articles, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Publisher's Correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Reviews for The Ink Truck, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Ads and Reviews, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Publisher Agreements, 1969-1974; 1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Royalty Statements, 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1984 Edition Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Ink Truck Reviews, 1984-1985; 1993; Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Legs, 1926-1988; Undated; 2; 4.42 cu. ft.
  This series focuses on Kennedy's second book Legs, the first in his "Albany Cycle" of novels. Published in 1975, Legs is a fictional account of the notorious Albany gangster Jack "Legs" Diamond. Included are multiple working and edited manuscript drafts spanning a period of several years, galley proofs, rejected and omitted pages, book reviews, profiles about Kennedy, book cover artwork, and correspondence with the publisher. There also are newspaper articles from the 1920s and 1930s about Legs Diamond which Kennedy used to conduct research on Diamond and the period. Please note the overall series dates are not inclusive.
  - First Draft of Legs, Rough Copy, 1968 December-1969 March (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - First Draft as Sold to Dial Press, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - First Draft, pages 1-134, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - First Draft with Author's Notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - First Draft with Rejected and Rewritten Pages, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Working Copy of Second Draft with Approved Pages, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Second Draft with Approved Pages, 1-110, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Third Draft, pages 111-227, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Working Copy of Third Draft in Sections, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Third Draft, Misc. Pages, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Third Draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fourth Draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Working Copy of Fourth Draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fourth Draft, Rejected from Washington Post, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Fatness" Version with Author Edits, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - "Fatness" Version, Unedited (Folder 1 of 2), Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Fatness" Version, Unedited (Folder 2 of 2), Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Fatness" Version (Fifth Draft), Misc. Pages, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
  - Final "Fatness" Version (Fifth Draft), Undated (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - Sixth Draft, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Working Copy of Sixth Draft, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sixth Draft, Rewrites and Rejected Pages, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sixth Draft with Author Edits, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Sixth Draft with Author Edits, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sixth Draft with Author Edits, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - Sixth Draft, Final Copy with Edits (Folder 1 of 2), 1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sixth Draft, Final Copy with Edits (Folder 2 of 2), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Seventh Draft, As Sold to Coward, McCann & Geoghegan (C.M.G.), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - Seventh Draft with Author Edits, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - Cut Pages from Seventh Draft, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Seventh Draft with Edits, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
  - Working Copy of Eighth Draft, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
  - Master Copy of Eighth Draft with Edits (Folder 1 of 2), 1974 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Master Copy of Eighth Draft with Edits (Folder 2 of 2), 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Transcript of Eighth and Final Draft, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
  - Final Draft with Edits, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
  - First Galley Proofs, 1975 (Oversized 2, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Edited Pages, Undated (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - Rejected Pages, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Omitted Pages with Edits, Undated (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
  - Newspaper Articles About Legs Diamond, 1926-1927; 1930-1931 (Oversized 3, Folder 1)
  - Dial Press Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - International Famous Agency (I.F.A) Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Coward, McCann & Geoghegan Booklets, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Coward, McCann & Geoghegan, Inc. Publishers Correspondence, 1974-1976; 1979; 1981 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Reviews and Publicity, 1974-1976; Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Reviews and Publicity, 1975; 1988; Undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Book of the Month Club Magazines, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - San Juan Star Profile of Kennedy, 1976 (Oversized 2, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Articles About Legs Diamond, 1979-1981; Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Original Color Artwork, Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Book Covers, Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Information, Undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Billy Phelan's Greatest Game, 1973; 1976-1978; 1985-1986; Undated; 3; 3.24 cu. ft.
  This series consists of multiple manuscript drafts, notes, and galleys for Kennedy's third novel Billy Phelan's Greatest Game, published in 1978. The story introduces the Phelan family that figures prominently in five additional Kennedy books. Set in Albany during the Depression, Billy Phelan is a small-time gambler and bookie who becomes involved in the kidnapping of a local political boss' son. More than half of the folders in the series contain Federal Bureau of Investigation records of the actual John J. O'Connell, Jr. kidnapping and subsequent extortion case in 1933. The O'Connell family was heavily involved in Democratic Party politics in Albany. Kennedy also corresponded with the Federal Bureau of Investigation about the O'Connell kidnapping and received additional case records after the publication of Billy Phelan's Greatest Game.
  - First Unfinished Draft, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - First Unfinished Draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Draft Pages, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Second Finished Draft, Unedited, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Second Finished Draft with Edits, As Sold to Viking, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Pages From Second Draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Working Copy of Second Draft with Edits, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Third Draft, Pages 1-179, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2-6)
  - Working Copy of Third Draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Third Draft with Author Edits, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Working Copy of Final Draft with Edits, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Editor's Copy of Final Draft with Notes, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Galley Proofs, 1977 (Oversized 1, Folder 6)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Volume 1, Section 3, O'Connell Case, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Section 4, O'Connell Case, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Section 5, O'Connell Case, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Section 6, O'Connell Case, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Section 7, O'Connell Case, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Section 8, O'Connell Case, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Section 9, O'Connell Case, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Section 10, O'Connell Case, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Volume 2, O'Connell Case, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Volumes 16-20, O'Connell Case, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Volumes 16-20, O'Connell Case, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Unlabeled or Unknown Sections, O'Connell Case, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
  - FBI Headquarters File: Unlabeled or Unknown Sections, O'Connell Case, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  - William Kennedy's FBI Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Ironweed, 1970; 1978-1982; 2003; Undated; 4; 1.26 cu. ft.
  This series consists almost entirely of manuscript drafts, edits, notes and galleys for the award-winning Ironweed, published in 1983. The novel, also set in Albany during the Depression, continues the story of the Phelan family. It focuses on Billy Phelan's father Francis, an alcoholic wanderer who returns to the city. Among its many honors, Ironweed received the National Book Critics Circle Award for Fiction in 1983 and the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction in 1984.
  The files document the evolution of the book from a short novel called The Lemon Weed about an alcoholic named Buddy, based upon an actual man Kennedy met and repeatedly interviewed during the 1960s. Of interest are photographs of men and women like Buddy in the streets and missions, taken by a photojournalist friend of Kennedy's and included in the first draft of The Lemon Weed for Subsistence Press.
  Please see Series 8, Ironweed (Film Version), for materials documenting the transition of the book to film.
  - Preface to The Lemon Weed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Lemon Weed with Missing "Helen" Section, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Lemon Weed Stories, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - First Draft of The Lemon Weed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Misc. Pages from The Lemon Weed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Lemon Weed: A Short Novel, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - First Draft for Subsistence Press with Images, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Copy of First Draft for Subsistence Press, No Images, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Incomplete Draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Author's Note to Self, "The Quest", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Three Page One Rewrites, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Completed First Draft of The Lemon Weed, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Original Manuscript, Pages 17-255, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Chapters IV and V for Howard Hausman, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - First Draft of Ironweed, Incomplete, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - First Draft with Edits, Incomplete, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Revised (Second) Draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Revised (Second) Draft with Edits, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chapter VI Revisions, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)